HONNOUJI ACADEMY
NATURALS ELECTION
KING OF THE HILL FINAL BATTLE
AND NOW...
CONQUEST OF THE BIG THREE
P
IP
RIP
D TRIP
IELD TRIP
ATTLEFIELD TRIP
BATTLEFIELD TRIP
D TRIP
LD TRIP
BATTLEFIELD TRIP
D TRIP
EFIELD TRIP
BATTLEFIELD TRIP
D TRIP
TTLEFIELD TRIP
LEFIELD TRIP
D TRIP
BATTLEFIELD TRIP
TRIP
EFIELD TRIP
TTLEFIELD TRIP
BATTLEFIELD
TRIP STRATEGY
MEETING
Sports club squads one through eleven,
preparations complete.
（猿投山(さなげやま)）運動部第１部隊から
第11部隊まで準備完了
Assigning to Osaka Battlefield Trip Brigade.
大阪制圧襲学(しゅうがく)旅団に配します
Culture club squads one through eighteen,
preparations complete.
（蛇崩(じゃくずれ)）文化部第１部隊から
第18部隊まで準備完了
Assigning to Kyoto Battlefield Trip Brigade.
京都制圧襲学旅団に配します
The Disciplinary Bureau is more than sufficient
for the Kobe Battlefield Trip Brigade!
（蟇郡(がまごおり)）神戸制圧襲学旅団は
強化風紀員だけで結構
Using a small, elite taskforce
is all well and good, but don't fail.
（猿投山）
少数精鋭はいいが失敗するなよ
Yeah, nobody wants to
see you commit seppuku, Ira.
（蛇崩）そうそう誰も苛(いら)ちゃんの
切腹なんか望んでないから
掃除も大変そうだし
It'd be a real mess cleaning
all your guts off the floor.
Worry not. We shall succeed.
（蟇郡）心配無用 結果は出す
I have formed an Intelligence and Tactics Team
with the Computer Club at its core,
（犬牟田(いぬむた)）パソコン部を中心に—
情報系クラスの二つ星生徒で
情報戦略班を編制
using Two-Star students from
the Information Systems class.
The information networks in each city
are already under our control,
各都市の情報網は掌握済み
and we are monitoring all communications
throughout their high schools.
各都市の高校の通信は
我々が全て監視しています
Iori, are the Special Ultima Uniforms ready?
（皐月(さつき)）伊織(いおり)
特殊極(ごく)制服の準備は？
Yes, milady. Development and
manufacture of the Anti-Osaka,
（スピーカー:伊織）はい
対大阪 対京都 対神戸
Anti-Kyoto, and Anti-Kobe Combat-spec
Ultima Uniforms are complete.
戦闘強化特殊極制服の
開発および製作は終了
They are being distributed to the
Battlefield Trip Brigades as we speak.
ただいま襲学旅団に配布中です
We are also producing new Three-Star
Ultima Uniforms for you Four Devas right now.
四天王の皆さんには
新しい三つ星極制服を製作中です
However, as the final adjustments are expected to take some time,
最終調整に
もう少し時間がかかるため
you will have to set out with the same
Special Ultima Uniforms as the other students.
ほかの生徒同様の特殊極制服で
出発していただきます
Your uniforms have been improved based on
your battles with Matoi Ryuuko and Harime Nui.
纏流子(まといりゅうこ)および針目縫(はりめぬい)との
戦闘データを基に—
改良した
期待して待て
They will not disappoint.
There is no shame in your defeat against
Godrobe Senketsu and Grand Couturier Harime Nui.
純粋生命戦維(せんい)である神衣(かむい)鮮血
高次縫製師である針目縫を
相手にしての敗北は恥ではない
Through trials,
you will mature even further.
貴様たちは まだ成長する
その通過儀礼にすぎない
It is merely a rite of passage.
And now, I look forward to
your maturation as commanders.
今回は貴様たちの指揮官としての
成長を期待する
Lead the Battlefield Trip Brigades to victory!
襲学旅団を指揮して勝利せよ！
Understood!
（四天王）はい！
Very well. The Battlefield Trip is set to leave
at 0200 hours the day after tomorrow.
（皐月）よし 襲学旅行の出発は
明後日０２００(まるふたまるまる)時とする
Understood!
Is the helicopter ready?
（皐月）ヘリの準備は？
（揃(そろい)）できております
It is, milady.
Thank you.
（皐月）ありがとう
EPISODE THIRTEEN
CRAZY FOR YOU
This is a world tailored to someone's whims and fancies
dareka ga katteni kimeta readymade na
I'll break free of its shackles
kyou wo nugisutete
RYUUKO
MATOI
And sprint toward my goal
hadashi de hashitte iku
Even if I lose my way
machigattatte
GAMAGOORI IRA
SANAGEYAMA UZU
JAKUZURE NONON
INUMUTA HOUKA
Or trip and fall
korondatte
INUMUTA HOUKA
MANKANSHOKU FAMILY
Those wounds will still create
surimuita itami mo
MANKANSHOKU
MAKO
MIKISUGI
AIKUROU
KINAGASE
TSUMUGU
An original future for me
original na ashita ni naru
KIRYUUIN
SATSUKI
I hold my destiny in my own hands
tsukiageta kono te ni nigirishimeta
And it shines ever so brightly
chikai ga hikari ni natte
So until the day I reach you
itsuka kimi ni todoku sono shunkan made
I don't have the time to sit around crying
naiteru hima nante nai kara
My burning passion pours out from within me
hamidashite shimatta atsui omoi ga
And shines like a star in the night sky
yozora de kagayaki dasu
I think I now understand
umarete kita imi ga
Why I was born
wakatta ki ga shita
I'll make all of my dreams come true
negaigoto wa zenbu kono te de
With my own hands
kanaeru
Boy, I wish I could go!
（マコ）行きたいな
行きたくないな でも行きたいな
I don't want to go! But I wish I could!
I do wish I could go! But I don't want to!
やっぱ行きたいな
でも行きたくないな
やっぱ でも行きたいな
But I really wish I could go anyway!
（美木杉(みきすぎ)）揺れる女心だね
A woman's heart is a fickle thing.
（マコ）そうなんです
I know, right?
It's not like being asked if you want to go
somewhere makes you want to go,
行きたいかって聞かれたら
行きたいわけじゃないですけど
でも行きたかったな〜 京都
but I sure would've loved to go to Kyoto!
ああ 君たちボンクラ生徒は
襲学旅行置いてきぼりか
So you short-bus students are getting
left out of the School Battlefield Trip, huh?
戦争みたいなもんですからね
Yeah, 'cause it's war out there, apparently.
I hate fighting, but it's a free trip!
戦いは嫌だけど でもタダですよ
タダで行けるんなら
行きたいじゃないですか
If you could go somewhere for free,
you'd want to go, right?
Kyoto! Kobe! Osaka!
京都！ 神戸！ 大阪！
（美木杉）ああ 全部違うね
You got them all wrong.
Kyoto is here. Kobe is here.
Osaka is here.
ここが京都 ここが神戸 ここが大阪
Wow! They're all really close together!
げげ！ ３つとも
近いじゃないですか
まあね 関西圏だからね
Pretty much. It's the Kansai region, after all.
It boggles my mind that you
managed to make it to high school.
満艦飾(まんかんしょく)君が どうして
高校生になれたのか不思議だね
It's my mind that's boggled!
不思議なのはこっちのほうです！
By the way, is Ryuuko still in a bad way?
ところで流子君は
まだ悪いのかい？
（マコ）流子ちゃん
制服着れない病なんです
Ryuuko's developed a sudden
aversion to wearing her uniform.
（マコ）暴走から目覚めたあと
すぐに学校に行ったんですけど
After she snapped out of her rampage,
she went straight to the school,
それから帰ってきてからは
なんか急にふさぎ込んで—
but after she came back,
she was all mopey for some reason.
She doesn't even try to
put on poor Senketsu.
鮮血ちゃん
着ようともしないんです
Ah, I see.
（美木杉）ハァ… そうか
You there.
（凪田(なぎた)）君！
（美木杉）え？
You're Mankanshoku Mako, aren't you?
（凪田）満艦飾マコ君だね？
（マコ）はい
Yes.
頼む 纏流子君に会わせてくれ！
Please! Take me to see Matoi Ryuuko!
You can trust me!
怪しい者じゃない
僕は凪田信二郎(しんじろう) 元新聞部だ
I'm Nagita Shinjirou,
formerly of the Newspaper Club!
FORMERLY
OF THE
NEWSPAPER
CLUB
NAGITA
SHINJIROU
Found him!
（風紀委員Ａ）いたぞ！
（風紀委員Ｂ）あそこだ！
There he is!
Hold it right there, newshound!
（風紀委員Ｃ）
そこを動くな 新聞部！
Crap!
しまった！
H-Hey, what are you doing?!
ちょ… ちょっと
何するんですか？
They're with the Disciplinary Bureau!
風紀部の連中だ
I can't let them find me!
ヤツらに見つかるとまずい
僕は登校禁止の身だから
I've been barred from school grounds!
Come back here!
But I don't even read the newspaper!
（風紀委員Ａ）待て待て
（風紀委員Ｂ）待たんか こらっ！
（マコ）え〜！ 私
新聞 読んでないのに！
Stop right there!
You're not getting away!
（風紀委員Ｃ）待て こら！
登校禁止ね
Barred from school grounds, huh?
I made you something, Ryuuko!
（好代(すくよ)）はい 流子ちゃん
（流子）これは…
What's that?
My special croquettes, made with
finely-chopped, super-mysterious ingredients!
（好代）とびっきりに
わけのわからないもの—
細かく刻んで突っ込んだ
スペシャルコロッケだよ
元気が出るよ
先に食べた又郎(またろう)たちが—
They'll get you back on your feet!
Matarou and the others had some earlier.
ほら！
See?
It's so wonderful to be alive!
Dance, Matarou!
（薔薇蔵(ばらぞう)）人生はバラ色だ！
踊れ 又郎！
（又郎）うん 俺は回るよ！
そ〜れ！ クルクル クルクル…
I'm twirling, Dad!
Round and round and round!
Spin, spin! Churn and turn into butter!
（薔薇蔵）回れ回れ！
回り続けて
バターになってしまえ！
I really turned into butter!
（又郎）ホントに
バターになってまった…
（薔薇蔵）トロトロに
溶けてまった
I feel like I've melted into goo!
I think those might be a bit dangerous.
（流子）これはちょっと
危ないんじゃ…
Anyway, eat up, get your body
moving, and sweat it out!
とにかく食べて 動いて 汗かいて
そしたら胸にたまった悪いものも
流れていってくれるから！
If you do that, all the bad things bottled up in your heart will flow right out of you!
（流子）あざっす
Thanks, ma'am.
（好代）ハァ…
I couldn't hold in my rage.
（流子）あのとき
私は自分の怒りを
抑えられなかった
All I wanted was to kill Harime Nui,
even if I had to destroy everything to do it.
全てを壊しても針目縫を殺す
そう思っていた
...Senketsu...
鮮血
Is it safe for me to wear you?
私はお前を着ていいのか
Please do!
（凪田）着てください
（流子）え？
（流子）何だ？
（凪田）ぜひ着てください
What the hell?
Please put it on!
Wh-Who are you?
だ… 誰だ？
...Mom, I brought a friend—
（マコ）
お母さん 今日 友達が…
あれ？ もう来てる
Oh, he's already inside!
（好代）いらっしゃい
Welcome!
HONNOUJI
NEWSPAPER
（マコ）え〜 何 何？
HONNOUJI
NEWSPAPER
It says "We Are Not
blankety-blank's blanks!"
“我々は の ではない”だって
わけのわからないことが
書いてあるね 流子ちゃん
Wow, there's all sorts of incomprehensible stuff written in here, Ryuuko!
（凪田）漢字も読んでくれ！
Read the kanji, too!
Kiryuuin Satsuki and the
Kiryuuin Conglomerate
（凪田）鬼龍院(きりゅういん)皐月と
鬼龍院財閥は—
学園の生徒たちを
兵士にしようとしている
are trying to turn the
academy's students into soldiers.
僕はそれが許せなかった
I couldn't let that happen.
だが校内新聞は
風紀委員の検閲に引っ掛かり
But the school paper ran afoul
of the Disciplinary Bureau censor,
and I was unable to
distribute it to the students!
生徒たちに配ることも
できなかった
自分の無力さを思い知らされた
It drove home just how powerless I truly am!
（マコ）なんと凪田さん
生徒会ににらまれて—
Nagita says he's gotten on
the Student Council's bad side
ずっと登校禁止だったんだって
and has been barred from
the school grounds ever since!
There is no freedom of speech in this school.
（凪田）
この学校に言論の自由はない
鬼龍院に逆らう者など１人もいない
There isn't a single person
who stands up to Kiryuuin.
そう思っていた だが君は違う！
Or so I thought. But you're different!
You defeated the Four Devas all by yourself
たった１人で四天王を破り
鬼龍院皐月すら恐れさせた
and struck fear into even Kiryuuin Satsuki!
You're Honnouji Academy's revolutionary!
君は本能字(ほんのうじ)学園の革命児だ
I can fight, too!
Just as long as you lead the way!
僕も戦える 君となら！
You'll have to fight by yourself.
（流子）
だったら１人で戦ってくれ
好きでやってんじゃねえんだ
帰ってくれ
I'm not fighting because I want to.
Get outta here! Beat it!
さあ！
What are you fighting for, then?!
じゃあ君は何のために
戦っているんだ
（流子）わかるか そんなもん
How the hell should I know?
You've reached one person, at least!
少なくとも １人いる
One man who saw what you'd done and took back his life!
君の姿を見て 人生を
取り戻した男が１人いる
Your fight hasn't been for nothing!
君の戦いは無意味じゃない
So put on that sailor uniform,
and fight one more time!
だから そのセーラー服を着て
もう一度 戦ってくれ！
（流子）
人のために戦ってんじゃねえ！
I don't fight for the sake of others!
Go on, beat it! Just give up and get out!
さあ！ 諦めて とっとと帰れよ
諦めないぞ纏君
I won't give up, Matoi!
君は僕の いや本能字学園に残った
善良なる希望の… うう…
...You are my—
...no, all of Honnouji Academy's—
virtuous star of hope!
（流子）うるせえ！
Quit it!
君から受けた勇気は—
...I won't let the courage you gave me...
go to waste! Farewell!
決して無駄にはしない！ では！
（流子）何なんだよ一体！
What the hell was that guy's problem?!
Ryuuko.
（鮮血）流子
（流子）うるさい 何も言うな
Zip it. Not a word out of you.
CO.
LTD.
AUDITORIUM
I put this question to you, gentlemen.
（羅暁(らぎょう)）
諸君らに問おう 服とは何か
What is clothing?!
Clothing is sin! Man's original sin!
（役員たち）
服とは罪 人間の原罪
（羅暁）そう 服とは罪
Indeed. Clothing is sin.
人は禁断の知恵の実を食べたとき
その裸体を恥じ—
When Man ate the forbidden fruit
of the Tree of Knowledge,
he became ashamed of his nakedness
and covered his nethers with fig leaves.
いちじくの葉で秘所を覆った
From the moment Man first gained free will as a human being,
人間は人間としての
意志を持ったときから
REVOCS CEO KIRYUUIN RAGYOU
it has been his fate to cover
his body in the clothing called "sin".
罪という名の衣を
身にまとうことを定めとしたのだ
Clothing made by REVOCS is sold in
ninety percent of the world's countries
我がＲＥＶＯＣＳ(リボックス)社の服は—
すでに全世界の
90パーセントの国で販売され
圧倒的なシェアを占めている
and controls an overwhelming
share of the market.
Why is that?
それは なぜか
Because we alone know man's sin
and create clothing for clothing's sake!
我々だけが人の罪を知り
服のための服を作っているからだ
I put the question to you again!
改めて問おう 服とは何か
What is clothing?
Clothing is the world!
（皐月）服とは世界
天と地と人を包み—
The grand will that binds the heavens, the earth, and mankind, covering all.
全てを覆わんとする大いなる意志
Indeed.
そう それこそがカバーズの意志
That is exactly the intent of COVERS.
How does Junketsu feel on you?
（羅暁）純潔の着心地はどうだ？
A rather powerful article
of clothing, is it not?
なかなか手ごわい服だろう？
うん なかなかよく着ているな
You wear it well.
ありがとうございます
Thank you, Mother.
Hououmaru.
（羅暁）鳳凰丸(ほうおうまる)
（鳳凰丸）はっ
Yes, ma'am.
Is this what brings you here today?
（羅暁）
今日来たのは この件かな？
Godrobe Senketsu, eh?
神衣鮮血か
ラ ヴィ エ ドロール
La vie est drôle.
I have already filed a report
regarding that incident.
（皐月）
そちらは すでに報告済みです
私の判断に任せるという言葉を
いただいております
You said that it would be
left to my discretion.
Of course.
（羅暁）
もちろん若い子は若い子同士
Matters should be settled youth
against youth, Godrobe against Godrobe.
神衣は神衣同士でケリをつける
いいことだと思うよ
That's the way it should be.
（皐月）
では なぜ高次縫製師など
本能字学園に送られた？
Why, then, was the Grand Couturier sent to Honnouji Academy?
The Grand Couturier?
高次縫製師？ ああ縫(ぬい)のことか？
あれはしかたない
Oh, you mean Nui? I had no choice.
芸術家の気まぐれは
いくらＣＥＯでも制御不能だ
Not even a CEO can rein
in the whims of an artiste.
I see.
なるほど ですが私の計画を
邪魔するものがいれば—
However, if anyone should
interfere with my plan,
私の判断で処置します
I will deal with them under my own discretion.
（羅暁）好きにやりなさい
Do as you wish.
“カバーズの子”として動く限り
世界はお前の味方だ
As long as you continue to
act in the interest of COVERS,
Revocs Market Shares
the world will remain your ally.
I shall set out on the Big Three
Battlefield Trip the day after tomorrow.
（皐月）明後日
三都制圧襲学旅行に出かけます
BIG THREE
BATTLE
FIELD TRIP
（羅暁）報告は受けている
何日かかる？
I've read your report.
How many days will it take?
（皐月）１日あれば十分
One day will be sufficient.
Magnificent.
（羅暁）すばらしい
With this, Honnouji Academy's rule over
all the schools in the country will be complete.
（皐月）
これで我が本能字学園の
全国学園支配が完成する
COMPLETE
RULE OF
ACADEMIES
COUNTRY
WIDE
日本中の全ての学園に—
REVOCS uniforms will be
supplied to every school in Japan.
REVOCS UNIFORMS IN
EVERY JAPANESE
ACADEMY
ＲＥＶＯＣＳの制服が
支給されることになるでしょう
（羅暁）
そして学生たちの裏に潜む
裸の猿どもも引きずり出す
And the naked apes lurking behind the students will be dragged out into the open.
NAKED APES
（皐月）よく おわかりで
You understand perfectly.
You have a reason to save
the Kansai region for last.
（羅暁）
関西を最後に残すからには
理由がある
私の娘なら そう考える
Or so I believe,
given that you are my daughter.
Leave everything to me.
（皐月）お任せください
鬼龍院の名に恥じぬ戦いを
お見せします
I shall show you a battle
worthy of the Kiryuuin name.
La vie est drôle.
“La(ラ) vie(ヴィ) est(エ) drole(ドロール)
人生は面白い”か
"Life is droll", eh?
It is. And it's about to get even more so.
ああ これからもっと
面白くなる
（縫）じゃあ僕は
好き勝手やるってことで
Well, I'm off to do things my own way.
I suggest you be careful.
Anger my daughter at your peril.
（羅暁）気を付けたまえ
私の娘は怒らせると怖いぞ
いいんじゃない？
そのくらいのほうが本気が見えて
Fine by me!
That way, we can see her go all out.
And that's something you
want too, isn't it, Lady Ragyou?
羅暁様も
それを望んでるじゃないの？
Yes, that's right.
（美木杉）ああ そうだ
These are the forces that
Honnouji Academy is mustering.
以上が本能字学園の戦力だ
本部にもデータを送っておいた
I've sent the data to HQ as well.
（携帯電話:黄長瀬(きながせ)）
いよいよ総攻撃ってわけか
So they're finally launching
an all-out assault, huh?
But thanks to your investigation, we have a tool we can use.
（黄長瀬）だが あんたの
調査のおかげで手が打てる
あの化け物女の相手を
するかと思うと気が重いけどな
It bums me out that we might have to
take on that monstrous girl, though.
It's rare to hear you complain, Tsumugu.
珍しいな 紬(つむぐ)が弱音か
（携帯電話:黄長瀬）
だが やらざるをえんな
But we have no choice but to do this.
たとえ裸のヌーディストに
なろうとも
Even if it means becoming naked Nudists.
僕もこっちの問題を
片づけてから向かうよ
I'll join you as soon as I deal
with a little problem of my own.
He really has been
suspended indefinitely, huh?
確かに無期限停学処分か
...It's just like he said, but still...
本人の言ったとおりだが…
Good morning, Mankanshoku!
おはよう 満艦飾君
Oh, Nagita! Is it okay
for you to be at school?
あっ 凪田さん
学校来ていいんですか？
（凪田）纏君はまた休みか
Matoi stayed home again, did she?
Yeah, she and the sailor uniform
were staring each other down again today.
（マコ）ええ 今日も
セーラー服とにらめっこしてた
I see. We have no choice, then.
（凪田）そうか しかたがない
僕たちでやるしかないな
We'll have to do it ourselves.
What's this?
これは？
（凪田）僕はもう逃げない
そう纏君に伝えてくれ
I'm done with running away.
Please tell Matoi that.
（拡声機:凪田）
登校中の本能字学園の生徒諸君
All students in attendance at
Honnouji Academy, lend me your ears!
聞いてくれ！
Can you not see that there is something wrong with how this academy is run?
君たちは この学園のやり方が
おかしいとは思わないか！
Obeying Kiryuuin Satsuki's every word
and then putting on Ultima Uniforms to fight?
鬼龍院皐月の言いなりになり
極制服を着て戦うなんて—
Don't you think that's wrong?!
おかしいとは思わないか！
さあ！ 満艦飾君
その新聞をまいて！
Go on, Mankanshoku!
Hand out those newspapers!
Hurry!
（凪田）早く！
Schoolmates! Let us take back
this academy together!
Thank you! Thank you! Read our paper! Thank you! Read all about it!
（マコ）よろしく！
よろしく！ よろしく！
（凪田）諸君 学園を
僕らの手に取り戻そう！
For the details, read this newspaper!
詳しくはこの新聞を読んでくれ！
...You two! Unauthorized soapboxing is against—
（風紀委員Ａ）
こら〜っ 貴様ら！
無許可での演説は…
Oh no! It's the Disciplinary Bureau!
（マコ）うわ〜っ
風紀委員だ〜！
Oh, no! Run, Mankanshoku!
いけない！ 満艦飾君は逃げろ！
（マコ）凪田さん無茶だよ
逃げて逃げて！
Nagita! Don't be a hero! Run! Run!
Never! I refuse to live in fear any longer!
（凪田）よせ！ 僕はもう
暴力には屈しない！
断固抵抗するぞ！
I will resist to my last breath!
とお〜！
He ran!
（風紀委員Ａ）逃げた逃げた！
（風紀委員Ｂ）追え追え！
After him!
You're not getting away!
Nagita!
（マコ）凪田さん！ うっ…
Mankanshoku!
What do you think you're doing?
（蟇郡）満艦飾
貴様は何をしている
ああ 蟇郡先輩
Gamagoori!
Under normal circumstances, your actions would
merit a one-month stay in the Time Out Chamber,
本来なら貴様の行為は
１カ月の反省房行きだが
but these are not normal circumstances!
今は有事である
I am commuting your sentence to hard labor in the School Raid Commissariat Unit!
襲学旅行兵站(へいたん)部の労働で
懲罰に変える
Now, load that cargo onto the trucks!
さあ！ この荷物を
トラックに積み込め！
（マコ）ひえ〜
Are you afraid of me, Ryuuko?
（鮮血）私が怖いのか 流子
No. I'm afraid of myself.
（流子）いや 怖いのは私だ
Back then, you were crying.
あのとき お前は泣いていた
You were pulled into my mind as I rampaged out of control,
暴走する私の心に引きずられて
怒りに染まった血を注ぎ込まれて
got pumped full of rage-filled blood,
had more power than
you wanted pulled out of you,
自分が望む以上の力を
引きずり出されて
and then you broke down and cried.
お前は泣いていた
Even then, I could tell
how bitter your tears were.
お前の涙の苦さ
私にもよくわかった
それでも私は自分が
止められなかった
But in spite of that, I couldn't stop myself.
マコがいなかったら
どうなっていたか
If Mako hadn't shown up,
I don't know what would have happened.
Did you forget what you said to me?
（マコ）流子ちゃん
言ってたじゃない
お父さんの敵を取るんじゃない
You said it wasn't about avenging your dad,
お父さんのことが知りたいんだって
but getting to know him better!
Even so, do not reject me.
（鮮血）それでも私を拒否するな
I want to be worn by you.
（鮮血）私は流子に着られたい
I was likely born for the express purpose of being worn by you.
たぶん私はお前に着られるために
生まれたのだ
Have you remembered something?
（流子）何か思い出したのか？
（鮮血）いや
ただそんな感覚がある
No. I just get that feeling.
And every time I drink your blood, that feeling grows stronger.
お前の血を吸うたび
その感覚が強くなる
Save me, Matoi!
助けてくれ纏君！
We have you now!
（風紀委員Ａ）悪い生徒は！
Take him away!
（風紀委員Ｂ）いね〜か〜！
（凪田）ごめん 君を
巻き込むつもりはなかったんだが
I'm sorry! I never intended to get you mixed up in all this!
Our dressers!
Our straw mats!
S-Stop it!
（薔薇蔵）ウチのたたみが
（又郎）タンスが
（流子）や… やめろ！
Our sliding screen!
だあ〜！
どは〜！
いや〜！
Pops!
（薔薇蔵のうめき声）
（又郎）おやじ！
（流子）おじさん！
Mr. Mankanshoku!
（凪田）纏君！
Matoi!
Prepare for surgery!
（好代）オペの準備よ！
（又郎）母さんオペできるの？
You know how to operate, Mom?!
Everyone has to start somewhere!
（好代）誰にでも最初はあるわ
Got it, Mom! I'll help!
（又郎）わかった！
母ちゃん 俺も手伝うよ
Senketsu, if I go too far,
I'll need you to stop me.
（流子）鮮血 私が行きすぎたら
お前が止めてくれよ
I cannot promise that.
（鮮血）それは約束できない
私を着るのは流子だ
It is you who wears me.
まったく！
融通の利かない服だよ お前は
Sheesh, you're not very flexible
for a piece of clothing, you know?
However, you were able to
bring yourself back under control.
（鮮血）
だがあのとき お前は止まった
自分の力でな
With your own willpower.
That is why I am not
frightened in the least.
だから私は何もおびえていない
Gotcha. We're all responsible
for our own actions.
わかった 何事も自己責任だ
What are you doing?! Stop it!
（殴る音）
（凪田）何をする！ やめろ！
Do what you will with me!
何をしても無駄だ
I will... never yield!
僕は絶対に屈しないぞ！
負けるもんか！
I won't be beaten!
Hold it!
（流子）待て！
その男をどうするつもりだ
What do you think you're doing to that guy?
ああ〜！ 纏君
Matoi!
Don't look at me like that.
しょっぱい声を出すんじゃないよ
見殺しにはできねえだろうが
You know I couldn't
stand by and do nothing.
No time to chat, huh?
問答無用ってわけか
しかたねえ いくぞ鮮血！
Have it your way. Let's do it, Senketsu!
Sword Scissor: Decapitation Mode!
片太刀鋏武滾流猛怒(かただちばさみぶったぎるもーど)
SWORD
SCISSOR:
DECAPITATION
MODE
"STRIPPED"
Thread Stripper!
OF THE
WILL
TO FIGHT!
Hey, these guys aren't human!
こいつら人間じゃない！
So you've finally gotten dressed, Ryuuko.
ようやく来てくれましたね
流子さん
凪田 てめえが仕組んだのか
Nagita... You set all this up?
Indeed! Those men were all my puppets!
そうだよ 彼らは僕の操り人形
And I guess you are too.
いや あなたもかな
Come again?
（流子）何だと？
Fear from when you lost control.
（凪田）
暴走による恐怖と神衣の拒絶
Rejection of your Godrobe.
But you conquered your fear in order to save the helpless.
だが弱者を救済するために
その恐怖を克服する
You're so predictable
that it's downright adorable!
あまりにも素直な反応で
かわいすぎますよ
アハハ
No! You can't be!
まさか貴様
Ta-dah!
じゃじゃ〜ん
Harime Nui! It was you all along?
（流子）針目縫 貴様だったのか！
The data is disappearing?
データが消えていく
...Then that boy really was—
やはり あの男は！
まずい 流子君！
Oh, no! Ryuuko!
What's got you all frowny?
（縫）何 怒ってるの？
HARIME NUI
Wasn't that a good rehabilitation for you?
いいリハビリになったでしょ？
Why devise this elaborate plot
just to get me to put on Senketsu?
私に鮮血を着せるために
こんな回りくどいマネを
Well, Lady Satsuki barred me
from the school grounds.
HARIME NUI
だって皐月様が
出入り禁止だって言うんだもん
I have my own problems,
I'll have you know.
HARIME NUI
こっちだって
いろいろ苦労してるのよ
Will you show me just how much power you can wring out of it this time?
HARIME NUI
さ 今度はどのくらいの力を
見せてくれるかな？
...You little—
クソが！
HARIME NUI
Come on, what's that?
It's nothing like last time!
何それ この間と全然違う
Bite me!
やかましい！
You really are afraid of yourself!
（縫）やっぱ怖いんだ自分が
I am not!
（流子）そんなことはない！
After all the trouble I've gone to,
you're still holding back.
（縫）せっかく僕が あれだけの
お膳立てをしてあげたのに
まだ迷ってるんだね
You're weaker than I thought.
思ったより弱いね 飽きちゃった
I'm bored!
もう おしまい
It's all over.
Sen... ketsu...
鮮血
You don't have what it takes
to wear a Godrobe.
（縫）君に神衣を着る資格はないよ
Go and join your father.
お父様に会いに行きな
Oopsie, you figured it out already?
あれれ もう気が付いた
Why are you here?
（皐月）なぜここにいる
（縫）ああ 怒ってる？
Are you mad?
There is only one way to deal with those who do not obey my orders.
私の命令を聞かぬ者に
行うことは ただ１つだ
やだな〜 マジだよ この人
Oh gosh, she really means it!
Would you like to undergo the blood purge?
血の粛清 受けてみるか
Fine, fine, I'll leave.
わかった わかった 消えるわよ
その子にも飽きたしね
I'm bored with her, anyway.
How disgraceful.
ぶざまな
Is this... Matoi Ryuuko's Godrobe?
（伊織）
これは纏流子の神衣ですか？
Its remains.
（皐月）その残骸だ
What shall I do with it?
（伊織）これをどうしろと？
Find suitable hosts,
and divide the scraps among them.
（皐月）適任者を選び
このはぎれをそれぞれに配れ
その上で襲学旅行での
戦闘データを集めさせろ
Then use them to gather combat data
during the Battlefield Trip.
Understood.
（伊織）了解しました
Three years of study here
at Honnouji Academy!
（皐月）本能字学園に学んで３年
This battle is the first step
towards realizing our ambitions!
この戦いは我々の
待望の第１歩である
I have but one command
to impose upon you: win.
私から送る言葉はただ１つ“勝て”
Honnouji Academy Big Three
Battlefield Trip, roll out!
本能字学園 三都制圧襲学旅行
出発せよ！
I-I'm going, too?!
（マコ）わ… 私も
行っちゃうんですか〜
We're going, Soroi.
（皐月）行くぞ 揃
（揃）はい
Yes, milady.
おっ 流子君
Ryuuko!
...Is that...
これは…
Before the bell rings
chime ga naru mae ni
I sneak out of school
kugurinuketa
Avoiding the adults' vacant stares
otonatachi no haiiro no me
The pointless conversations
tawai no nai kaiwa
Keep going on and on
togirenu mama
As I walk down the slope
sakamichi wo kudatteku
I have nothing to do
nani wo suru demo naku
And nowhere to go
yuku ate sae mo naku
Right now, all I do
tada atashi ima wa ne
Is ignore any and all warnings
donna chuukoku mo mimi wo surinukeru
Because I still want to be free
mada mada suki ni sasete
I'm sorry, but it's not like me
gomen ne e ni kaita you na
To be an exemplary student
yuutosei wa rashiku nai wa
So I undo two of my shirt buttons
shirt no button wo futatsu hazushite
And take the back alley
rojiura no nukemichi
A path of mysterious sweet temptation
amai yuuwaku wa michi
Some things I've kept hidden from everyone
dare ni mo mada hanashite nai
But tonight, I will reveal my secrets to you
atashi no himitsu wo kon'ya oshiete ageru
NEXT EPISODE PREVIEW
（鮮血）
修学旅行は若き日の思い出作り
Field trips are the source
of many youthful memories,
YOUTHFUL MEMORIES
だが本能字学園は ひと味違う
BUT
but they're a little different
at Honnouji Academy!
A LITTLE
DIFFERENT
Theirs is a battlefield trip to conquer the
Big Three cities of Kobe, Kyoto, and Osaka!
神戸 京都 大阪
三都制圧襲学旅行
BIG THREE
BATTLEFIELD TRIP
彼らの青春アルバムは
真っ赤な血の色で描かれる
The album of their youth
is drawn in a deep, blood red!
ALBUM OF
THEIR YOUTH
BLOOD RED
次回 キルラキル
「急げ 風のように」
Next time on KILL la KILL,
"Ride Like the Wind"!
EPISODE 14
RIDE LIKE THE WIND